A Guide to the Virginia Tech Faculty Women's Club Records, 1965-2008
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
Virginia Tech Faculty Women's Club Records, 1965-2008
Special Collections, Virginia Tech, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms1997-014
10.4 cu. ft. 11 boxes
The collections consists of records and scrapbooks from the Virginia Tech Faculty Women's Club.
Virginia Tech Faculty Women's Club.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Acquisition Information
The Virginia Tech Faculty Women's Club Records have been donated to Special Collections in multiple accruals, beginning in 1997. Future donations are likely, as the organization remains active.
Historical Note
This organization was founded in 1965 as a social group to promote fellowship among women associated with Virginia Tech. The club currently strives to expand the intellectual and social horizons of its membership through enlargement of friendships, engagement in adult educational activities, scholarships, and promoting the interests of Virginia Tech.
Scope and Content
The records include correspondence, financial records, officers' job descriptions, newsletters, information about scholarships, cookbook sales, nursery operations, as well as annual scrapbooks of activities illustrated with photographs and newspaper clippings. Current holdings of records and papers date from the organization's beginnings in 1965 through 2008. The scrapbooks cover events from 1966 to 2008.
The collection is accompanied by printed annual yearbooks that include lists of members. (The yearbook volumes are cataloged and housed in Special Collections, call number HQ1905 V5 V5 SPEC).
Arrangement
The collection is arranged to two series: Series I: Records and Papers, 1965-2008 and Series II: Scrapbooks, 1966-2008. Series I: Records and Papers includes agendas, copies of cookbooks compiled by the group, correspondence, administrative records, membership information, meeting minutes, newsletters, and paper relating to programs, scholarships, and community activities. This series is arranged alphabetically by type of record.
Series II: Scrapbooks contains organization-created scrapbooks featuring photographs, newsclippings, programs, and materials relating to events. Each scrapbook is labeled with the year(s) covered. This series is arranged in chronological order.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Separated Materials
Virginia Tech Faculty Women's Club Records also include yearbook volumes, which are housed in Special Collections (call number: HQ1905 V5 V5 SPEC).
Index Terms
Corporate Names:
Virginia Tech Faculty Women's Club.
Subjects:
Faculty; University Archives; Virginia Polytechnic Institute; Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Contents List
- Series I: Records and Papers, 1965-2008
  - Agendas (Box-folder 1-1)
  - Cookbooks (Box-folder 1-2)
  - Correspondence Folder 1 of 2 (Box-folder 1-3)
  - Correspondence Folder 2 of 2 (Box-folder 1-4)
  - Executive Board (Box-folder 1-5)
  - Financial Records (Box-folder 1-6)
  - Interest Groups (Box-folder 1-7)
  - Membership (Box-folder 1-8)
  - Minutes Folder 1 of 5 (Box-folder 2-1)
  - Minutes Folder 2 of 5 (Box-folder 2-2)
  - Minutes Folder 3 of 5 (Box-folder 2-3)
  - Minutes Folder 4 of 5 (Box-folder 2-4)
  - Minutes Folder 5 of 5 (Box-folder 2-5)
  - Newsletters Folder 1 of 3 (Box-folder 2-6)
  - Newsletters Folder 2 of 3 (Box-folder 2-7)
  - Newsletters Folder 3 of 3 (Box-folder 2-8)
  - Nursery (Box-folder 3-1)
  - Officer Job Descriptions (Box-folder 3-2)
  - Programs (Box-folder 3-3)
  - Recording Secretaries' Papers (Box 4)
  - Scholarships (Box-folder 3-4)
  - Yearbook Material (Box-folder 3-5)
- Series II: Scrapbooks, 1966-2008
  - 1966, 1970-1974, 1975-1976, 1978-1983, 1983-1984 (Box 5)
  - 1986-1987, 1995-1996 (Box 10)
  - 1987-1988, 1988-1989, 1989-1990, 1990-1991, 1991-1992 (Box 6)
  - 1992-1993, 1993-1994, 1994-1995 (Box 7)
  - 1996-1997, 1997-1998, 1998-1999, 2004-2005 (Box 11)
  - 1999-2000, 2000-2001, 2001-2002, 2002-2003, 2003-2004, 2005-2006 (Box 8)
  - 2006-2007, 2007-2008 (Box 9)